<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Harpers Ferry ]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Harpers Ferry ]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/harpersferry/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:38:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/harpersferry/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Living with the Past - Residential Life in the Ferry]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Living with the Past - Residential Life in the Ferry</h1><p>If you lived here you'd be home by now! Harpers Ferry residents typically share a love of the landscape, the history, and the hallowed ground they live on.  Many agree that they are temporary stewards of the older homes, and cherish the unique 18th century village.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/41512f37e828937dd899d09d52bc303ba0d1227f.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/harpersferry/living-with-the-past-residential-life-in-the-ferry/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8fd29787-4984-4e14-9e9a-14aceb96550a</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:35:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Niagara Movement Centennial Commemoration at Harpers Ferry National Historical Park]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Niagara Movement Centennial Commemoration at Harpers Ferry National Historical Park</h1><p>By the end of the 19th century, the promise of freedom and equality for blacks had been buried by Jim Crow laws and legal segregation. To combat these injustices, Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois and other leading African-Americans created the Niagara Movement, which held its second conference (but first conference on American soil) on the campus of Storer College in 1906.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/c250f61358d8c2a0c5b13bab41ea5458178a35bd.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://vimeo.com/92507573</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0ca3d8f9-36f3-4084-8902-5dfdaef2d2ac</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Storer College: A Legacy of Light and Learning Excerpt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Storer College: A Legacy of Light and Learning Excerpt</h1><p>Storer opened in 1867 as a mission school to educate former slaves. For twenty-five years Storer was the only school in West Virginia that offered African Americans an education beyond the primary level. Following the Civil War, the Reverend Dr. Nathan Cook Brackett established a Freewill Baptist primary school in the Lockwood House on Camp Hill. Brackett's tireless efforts to establish freedmen's schools in the area inspired a generous contribution from philanthopist John Storer of Sanford, Maine, who offered $10,000 for the establishment of a school in the South. The donation was offered on the condition that the school be open to all regardless of sex, race or religion. On October 2, 1867, "Storer Normal School" was opened, and two years later, in December 1869, the federal government formally conveyed the Lockwood House and three other former Armory residences on Camp Hill to the school's trustees. Frederick Douglass served as a trustee of Storer College, and delivered a memorable oration on the subject of John Brown here in 1881. In 1954, legal segregation was finally ended by the landmark school desegregation decision handed down by the Supreme Court in Brown v. The Board of Education. The decision, however, brought an end to federal and state funding for Storer College, and a year later it closed its doors. Today the National Park Service continues the college's educational mission by using part of the old campus as a training facility.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/da398e1cd35038278b237d997499564073301da4.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://vimeo.com/92506899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d8480d6e-22ea-405a-bb1a-f202be3de49d</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:31:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Return of the 126th New York]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Return of the 126th New York</h1><p>In 2012-2013, Harpers Ferry National Historical Park continued its partnership with Harpers Ferry Middle School to produce student-created videos about Harpers Ferry's history. This is the fifth year of the project, and this year the focus is on the year 1863.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/c1cf3304aae3baef15c554b310e183f3fa86a30e.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzx8gsoi72c</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f0a8ca0a-adde-42e6-accf-2dd3c1d98407</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:31:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2013 Harper Ferry Middle School Vodcasts - Behind the Scenes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>2013 Harper Ferry Middle School Vodcasts - Behind the Scenes</h1><p>In 2012-2013, Harpers Ferry National Historical Park continued its partnership with Harpers Ferry Middle School to produce student-created videos about Harpers Ferry's history. This is the fifth year of the project, and this year the focus is on the year 1863.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/1643f94cc1504128c0f940dda6f969cc774c3add.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OiT-91WYDjo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6cb7543c-df4c-4e6c-a73d-f9e14308521f</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:28:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overview of the Of the Student, By the Student, For the Student service learning project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Overview of the Of the Student, By the Student, For the Student service learning project</h1><p>Of the Student, By the Student, For the Student (TM) is a program created, developed, and sponsored by Journey Through Hallowed Ground Partnership at the request of the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, in conjunction with Harpers Ferry National Historical Park and Harpers Ferry Middle School.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/4bea028de52ea2c4a8f993e2207ab3c7ed446d5b.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hO6c2vtiSXU</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b0337575-eecd-4724-bcd4-d12911aa2694</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D.C. getaway guide: 12 drivable weekend trips]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>D.C. getaway guide: 12 drivable weekend trips</h1><p>The West Virginia town is one big confluence — history and culture, mountains and rivers, urbane strollers and outdoorsy folks. The national historical park dominates the Lower Town, where the Potomac and Shenandoah rivers converge and Maryland, Virginia and West Virginia meet. The park spotlights seminal events including Civil War battles (and the revolving door of occupiers), the rise of industry and transportation, the arsenal raid by abolitionist John Brown and the movement to educate African Americans. Etsy-spirited boutiques, art galleries and snug cafes line Washington Street, the main drag, and outlying lanes. The area also has a spider’s web of hiking trails, including a section of the mother of all treks, the Appalachian Trail. The trail conservancy’s visitor center is a resource to all guests — long-distance marchers as well as day-walkers wearing flip-flops and carb-loading on waffle cones from Scoops.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/10e735a66337bb1fd30b6a000a57005eca62f7af.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/lifestyle/2015-regional-drives/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ca3714a5-8d70-4b26-b9bd-41f4a77bdd59</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 17:13:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harpers Ferry Cemetery Eagle Scout project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Harpers Ferry Cemetery Eagle Scout project</h1><p>This is "Harpers Ferry Cemetery Eagle Scout project" by midge on Vimeo, the home for high quality videos and the people who love them.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/920ff8e3b9cd734c27e80aa430194de5bd334945.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://vimeo.com/100325290</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">73cfe030-f9c6-4e24-8668-6b2e635340fc</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 04:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harpers Ferry Music On The Ridge June 2015 Highlights Video]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Harpers Ferry Music On The Ridge June 2015 Highlights Video</h1><p>Harpers Ferry Music on the Ridge is a concert series presented by the Harpers Ferry Parks & Recreation Commission. The concerts are a local favorite, and have become the signature musical event in the Historic Harpers Ferry residential area.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/8941797c5cc04afd4c73ff158ef079f5145c3db1.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://vimeo.com/130033726</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">111474e5-fa76-41ec-b51a-549461cc9890</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 04:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baptism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Baptism</h1><p>This is "Baptism" by midge on Vimeo, the home for high quality videos and the people who love them.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/5ee5497af2efacb3f6b68ae0a43f89136db9ab26.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://vimeo.com/83448584</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">14b6a578-e005-4b71-8848-5ecae72035c4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 04:06:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>